# Franklin Henderson

#### **CONTACT**

- work@fhwrdh.net
- mesume.fhwrdh.net
- franklin.henderson.pdf

#### **SKILLS**

- Js JavaScript, React, Node
- **3** HTML, CSS
- Webpack, Gulp, Jest, etc.
- m npm, GitHub, GitLab
- {} JVM, Java
- **C#** .Net, C#
- SQL, NoSQL
- XP, TDD, Pairing
- 4 Agile, Kanban, Scrum
- Y Leadership, Mentoring

#### **USER GROUPS**

- **WLVJS** Co-Organizer, Current
- Lunch.js Champion, Current
- S.LA, Current
- \* ALT.NET, Dublin, 2009-2011

#### **EDUCATION**

- CSUN, Math
- Santa Monica College, CS
- College of Marin, CS

#### **INTERESTS**

Brewing

#### **ABOUT ME**

Software professional with more than 20 years of experience building scalable, testable, maintainable systems across multiple technology platforms.

Proven history of leadership, both formally as a development manager and informally mentoring developers and organizations on agile practices, test-driven development, front end technology.

Strong agile project management, analysis and presentation skills.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

## Senior Manager of Software Engineering CJ Affiliate

Feb 2018 - Present Westlake Village, Ca

Manage a department of 40+ software engineers, coaching teams on execution, agile development, release planning, backlog management.

Work closely with Product Management organization on prioritization, release planning, agile development.

Responsible for department-wide staffing including interviews, annual reviews, salary, etc.

## Principal Engineer / Team Lead / Front End Chapter Lead CJ Affiliate

Jan 2015 - Feb 2018 Westlake Village, Ca

As the Automation Team Lead, I led a young and inexperienced but talented team. Facing tight, immovable deadlines and an at-risk client, the team took a rough prototype and delivered a robust, high performance system for testing the correctness and regulatory compliance of publisher websites with respect to affiliate offers. The system scales to a theoretical capacity greater than 500k tests per day. Duties included full stack development, user interface design, agile planning guidance, product demonstrations and direct customer engagement. Team management duties included regular 1-1 meetings, annual reviews, career mentorship.

As the Front End Chapter Lead, I managed a department-wide group of developers and designers as we worked to improve the quality and consistency of the front end code produced leading to better, more consistent products for our customers. The group is responsible for providing guidance to the broader department on front end technologies, training, coding standards, and best practices. The group also oversees



**≥** Travel

Music

development of the open source Visual Stack library of reusable components.

As a member of the Insights team, I developed an early prototype front end application used to demonstrate the insights concept and explore requirements with customers and internal stakeholders. The application was featured prominently in the 2016 CJU Solutions Lounge.

I led a small team working on modernizing CJ's flagship front end application. The Account Manager is used directly by customers as well internal staff to create, administer and report on affiliate programs. Our team migrated the application code to ES6 JavaScript, introduced a modern build pipeline based on npm, Gulp and Webpack.

Built an agile project management tool on top of Atlassian Jira to facilitate release planning and backlog management. While the original intention was to simply plug a small gap in the Jira toolset for a single team, it has grown in depth and breadth and is now used company wide to provide a fact-based snapshot of project progress over time.

## Senior Software Engineer CJ Affiliate

Jan 2014 - Jan 2015 Westlake Village, Ca

Delivered a mobile SDK for event tracking in IOS applications. Included development and publication to the App Store of a full IOS application containing the SDK. This project required me to quickly learn Objective C, XCode and how to navigate the App Store publishing process.

Delivered a new Developer Portal allowing customers and third party developers access to the IOS and Android Tracking SDKs and documentation on how to use them.

## Principal Developer

### Super Stealth Startup

#### Apr 2012 - Jan 2014 Thousand Oaks, Ca

Hired to build a next generation display advertising system. Collaboratively designed, coded, tested and managed an application that implemented complex rulesets across multiple advertising networks, user attributes and geographic configurations. Node.js, CoffeeScript, MongoDB, AWS, Mocha.

Designed and implemented data migration tools to ETL ad server data into a reporting-friendly schema. Node.js, CoffeeScript, PostgreSql, MySql, AWS.

Designed, coded and managed a web-based application providing near-realtime KPIs, including configuration settings, impression statistics, CPMs, revenue. Node.js, CoffeeScript, Express, Bootstrap, Mocha.

Maintainance and light development of a number of Google Chrome Extensions. JavaScript.

In an organization with no project management staff, I captured and documented project backlog ideas that had been previously whiteboarded informally.

## **Principal Developer**

#### TrueCar

#### Sep 2011 - Apr 2012 Santa Monica, Ca

Hired to form the nucleus of a new Internal Applications team, created to aggregate and modernize various legacy financial and internal business process applications. Led the interview and hiring process.

Introduced TURBO, an internal-facing, web-based portal as a home for migrated and future interfaces produced by the team.

Rewriting the legacy financial application was the first priority. ASP.NET MVC, Castle Windsor, NUnit, Rhino Mocks.

Delivered multiple data migration applications compliant with the company's extensive data security policies. Collaborated with database team to build and deploy the required SQL to support these applications.

Oversaw the successful upgrade and migration of an existing Microsoft Dynamics GP server and 15+ client installations. This included working with both outside consultants, TrueCar support engineers and end users to ensure business continuity via extensive testing and security audits.

## **Development Manager**

#### **Pocket Kings**

#### May 2009 - Sep 2011 Dublin, Ireland

Assembled and managed a team of nine developers responsible for multiple web applications. Duties included hiring, annual reviews, sprint planning, regular progress reports to CTO, CEO.

Technical project leadership on a number of key operations-focused development projects. For example, CS Live Chat gives customer service agents the ability to initiate contact with customers through an internal web interface connected to both the payment system and the core game system. Responsibilities included functional specification support, authoring high-level technical design documents, full stack development, QA test plan approval, product demos to business stakeholders, production deployment and ongoing performance monitoring.

Led efforts to consolidate multiple, heterogeneous, internal applications / interfaces under a single secure, maintainable, tested application.

Reversed engineered and ported code from Python, PHP and Java into .NET.

Cross team project and sprint planning, including specification reviews, high level estimation and scheduling.

Created and delivered multiple introductory presentations for all IT new hires explaining the enterprise architecture of the company as it relates to Tools applications.

#### **Technical Lead**

#### **Pocket Kings**

#### Mar 2005 - May 2009 Los Angeles, Ca / Dublin, Ireland

Hired as the first member of new Tools team to architect and implement a web-based customer service / business process application.

Supported 300+ concurrent, geographically distributed CSRs and interacted with proprietary core gaming engine. The application allowed CSRs to view and manage player account data and interact with various other systems. Original design allowed rights- protected interaction with the game and databases in a variety of capacities: customer support, cashier, marketing/promotions, affiliate management, operations, fraud and game security. C#, ASP.NET, WCF, MSSQL.

Initiated Domain Driven Design-inspired re-architecture of the application in response to the evolving enterprise architecture and business requirements.

Initiated agile within the IT organization. Hired the company's first ScrumMaster and began organizing work around sprints. Team success led to Scrum adoption across the company.

Responsible for software design documents, unit testing methodologies, automated build scripting and deployment planning.

Participated in interviewing and hiring decisions for positions throughout the IT organization.

## Senior Software Engineer

#### Movielink

#### May 2002 - Mar 2005 Santa Monica, Ca

First member of newly created Business Systems team. Took ownership of customer account management (CAM) application. CAM acted as a customer service representative's interface to the Movielink system, allowing agents to issue refunds and credits, rent on behalf of customers, reset passwords, review account history and search the product catalog. Java, ATG Dynamo, Oracle.

Inherited a partially completed set of UNIX shell and Perl scripts that gathered data from Apache logs and an Oracle database and populate a NetGenesis reporting database. Rewrote scripts to add error handling, performance tracking, the ability to run the entire suite unattended, and publish results to an internal distribution list. Implemented web-based run-time tracking system.

Designed and implemented Royalty and Commission Calculator to calculate royalties for content providers and commissions for marketing affiliates according to complex rules specified by contracts.

### **Software Engineer**

#### **Day Software**

#### Oct 2001 - May 2002 Orange County, Ca

Part of a new team assembled primarily to create Java connectors to third party data sources from Day's flagship content management product, Communiqué Unify. Using the Communiqué 3.0 ContentBus architecture, these connectors provide access and ContentBus services (text search, versioning, etc) on top of external data sources.

Wrote specs and code to connect Communiqué to IBM's Enterprise Information Portal. EIP provides a federated view and search capabilities across a number of IBM data sources (MQ Series, DB2, Content Manager, etc.)

Worked closely with Day partners from Germany to develop the requirements and initial specification for an SAP connector.

Completed initial implementation and started porting to JCA architecture. Maintained and developed Day's sales demonstration product.

## **Software Engineer**

#### Post Communications / Netcentives

#### Oct 1999 - Oct 2001 San Francisco, Ca

Senior member of platform development team for Email Marketing Group. Primarily responsible for performance, reliability and scalability of PostDirect's delivery subsystem. Java, JavaScript, Oracle, SMTP.

Implemented multi-threaded, distributed architecture. Leader / follower model used to breakup data retrieval, email personalization, email delivery. Features included highly parallel system (1600+ Java threads per machine), leader / follower election process and failover mechanism for maximum availability. Introduced JUnit testing framework. Developed guidelines within the core engineering team for unit testing Java code.

Created web-based monitoring tools for the operations team. Tools monitored system activity, performance, machine memory / CPU usage, and upcoming scheduled deliveries.

### **Technical Lead**

#### Styleclick.com

#### Jan 1999 - Oct 1999 Los Angeles, Ca

Managed 4-6 member engineering team for flagship e-commerce website. Duties included full stack development, prioritization, scheduling, hiring, project management, code review, reporting to management.

Responsible for overall website robustness, reliability and uptime. Solely responsible for staging and deployment of Java and HTML to multiple production servers. Java, JavaScript, HTML.

### **Software Engineer**

#### Styleclick.com

#### Dec 1997 - Jan 1999 Los Angeles, Ca

Primary engineering resource during prototyping and technology evaluation stages of Styleclick.com project. Full stack development. Responsible for deployment to production servers.

Responsible for all HTML / CSS / JavaScript code for desktop CD-ROM product, published by Sierra Home. Implemented as a 10K LOC JavaScript application on top of the Internet Explorer 4 ActiveX control, integrating user interface with proprietary ActiveX controls. Extensive use of early browser DOM and event model. JavaScript, CSS, IE4!